所有工人  请离开建筑工地
All workers, please clear the construction site.
他们就不能在上班时间发现尸体吗
Why can't they find bodies between 9:00 and 5:00?
早起的鸟儿才有虫吃
Well, early bird gets the collar.
他来的比我还早
He was here before I was.
你终于来了  你一定会喜欢这个
Oh! Finally, you are here. You are gonna love this.
表演结束了
Come on, show's over!
正在进行犯罪现场调查  谢谢合作
Active crime scene. We appreciate your cooperation.
很可怕吧  我的第一件悬案
Awesome, right? My first cold case.
别这样  这案子挺有趣的
Come on, it's a little funny.
没什么有趣的  她被冻成冰块了
Not so much funny as true. She's frozen solid.
昨天夜里气温是多少
What was the temperature last night?
摄氏7度
Mid-40s.
不是因为暴尸在外才冻成这样的
It wasn't exposure.
案发现场一直有人
Site's active.
这儿的人说  昨晚她肯定没在这儿
The boys tell me there's no way she was here last night.
她正在融化
She's melting.
该找找红宝石鞋(源自绿野仙踪)
Maybe we should be looking
(轻敲鞋跟就能回家)
For ruby slippers.
是啊  你找的时候
Yeah, while you're at it,
顺便再找找会飞的猴子
Why don't you look for some flying monkeys?
也许是它们把她摆在那的
Maybe they left her here.
有什么发现吗
So what do you got for me?
尸体上找到了
There are pieces of plastic on her body
西装袋的塑料膜
From the garment bag.
所以她曾被装在西装袋内
So she was inside the bag?
除此之外  她还需要点时间才能完全融化
Other than that, it's gonna take a while for her to thaw.
我能肯定  她被搬到这里的时间不长
I can tell you she hasn't been here long.
也许只有几个小时
Maybe couple of hours.
这儿的安保措施怎么样
What about security?
钢丝网  有把钳子就能进来
Chain-link. Pair of bolt cutters took care of that.
看来凶手是想
Looks like our guy was hoping
把她埋在混凝土里
She'd disappear into the concrete pour.
再多浇几英尺  她就会被埋了
A few more feet, and she would've.
有点奇怪
It's kind of odd--
要埋尸  为什么还费神把她冻上呢
Taking the trouble to freeze a body and then dumping it?
这表现出了两种想法
We got two personality types working here.
凶手把尸体冻起来
A killer who freezes a body is a keeper
作为纪念品
He wants a souvenir.
但是又弃尸在这儿
But a guy who dumps a body?
是不想再和这案子有关联
Doesn't want to be reminded of the crime.
好了  我去围墙外面看看
All right, I’m gonna go check out the fence.
拍张面部特写
Get a close-up of her face.
和失踪人口作比对
I want to run her through missing persons.
太棒了  就像探索频道播的那样
Oh, cool, like on the discovery channel,
你们会把照片
Where you plug the photo into
存入面部识别数据库
Facial recognition databases?
-是的  就像那样  -太棒了
- Yeah, just like that. - Yes!
欢迎光临本局官方
Welcome to the department's official
面部识别数据库
Facial recognition database.
要手动查找
By hand?
似乎倒退到有数字录像机之前
That's like life before tivo.
也许你在手机上
Maybe you could download an app
下载个程序  就可以
On that phone of yours. You could just--
失踪人口还真多
There are a lot of missing people.
我们总会有办法找到他们的
One way or another, we'll find them
有的人死了
Some end up dead,
有的人出现在亚特兰大市郊的大房子
Some turn up in a double-wide
和年轻的白人脱衣舞女混在一起
With a stripper named Trixie outside Atlantic city.
还有的人  再也没出现过
And some just don't turn up.
达娜·苏利文
Dana Sullivan.
她和男朋友离开俱乐部的时候
Mm-hmm. Her and her boyfriend leave a club.
她男朋友接到个电话
He's a couple steps behind her
所以落在她后面几步
'Cause he gets a call on his cell phone.
她仅仅早几秒走过街角
She turns a corner just a few seconds before he does.
等他走过来的时候  她就不见了
And when he comes around, she's gone.
街道空空荡荡  没有车  什么都没有
Street's totally empty-- no traffic, no nothing.
相隔不到一米  她就这么消失了
In a matter of 3 feet, she literally just disappeared.
人不会从地球表面消失的
People don't disappear off the face of the earth.
当然会
Sure they do.
量子物理  外星人绑架  薛定谔的猫
Quantum physics, alien abductions, Schrodinger's cat.
前一分钟  你还在公园里买热狗
One minute, you're getting a hot dog in the park.
下一分钟  你就被带到空间裂隙中
The next, you're fighting off Sleestaks
和爬行动物激战(《失落的大陆》剧情)
On the far side of a dimensional rift.
我不相信  肯定有个合理的解释
I don't buy it. There's got to be an explanation
一个让一切都合情合理的故事
A story that makes everything make sense.
好吧  卡塞尔
Okay, Castle,
这具无名女尸的故事是什么呢
What's our Jane Doe's story?
虽然我不知道故事的起因
Well, I don't know how it starts,
但我知道结果  在建筑工地呈冰块状
But I know how it ends-- frozen at a construction site.
撇开会飞的猴子不谈  第一个疑点
So flying monkeys aside, what's the first question?
她是怎么到那里的
How did she get there?
鉴于尸体的冻结程度
Considering she was frozen solid,
她应该被藏匿在工地附近
She had to have been kept pretty close.
不一定
Not necessarily.
这儿是工地  但藏尸处
Here is the site. Her body might not
可能没你想的那么近
Have been kept as close as you might think.
冰冻的尸体融化需要很长时间
It takes a long time for a frozen body to thaw.
怎么  为了写书  你也冻过尸体
What, you, uh, freeze a body once for one of your books?
没有  但我在感恩节时做过火鸡
No, but I cooked a turkey for thanksgiving.
28磅重  一整晚才化开
It was a 28-pounder. It took all night to unfreeze.
她是个人  卡塞尔  不是火鸡
She's a person, Castle, not a turkey.
只是表明下看法
Just making a point.
好的  马上就来
Okay. I'm on my way.
蕾妮查到死者身份了
Lanie’s got an I.D.
这些留给你们处理
You'll take care of these?
莱恩  你能不能  谢了
Hey, Ryan, can you, uh... Thanks.
梅勒妮·卡瓦诺  死亡年龄34岁
Melanie Kavanaugh, 34 at time of death.
死因是头部遭钝器重创
Turns out c.o.d. was blunt-force trauma to her head.
怎么查到她的身份的
How'd you get her I.D.?
系统里有她的指纹记录
Her fingerprints were in the system.
-为什么  -藏匿毒品的轻罪
- For? - Misdemeanor drug possession.
她看起来不像是瘾君子啊
She doesn't look like a junkie.
是的  可以说  她身体状况良好
No, she's in pretty good shape, considering.
鉴于尸体没有起霜或组织变性
But judging the lack of frost and tissue degeneration,
因此藏尸地点
I'd say wherever she was stored,
温度变化不大
The temperature rarely varied.
-比如冷藏柜  -冷藏柜能达到这种效果
- Like a freezer. - Freezer'd do the job.
她死了多久了
How long has she been dead?
考虑到她处于这种状态的时长
Well, considering how long she's been like this,
还有尸体分解程度
Factoring decomposition,
她可能是在被杀后
I'd say she probably was frozen
24小时内被冻住
Within 24 hours of being killed.
她处于这种状态的时长是指
What do you mean, "how long she's been like this"?
根据我调出的报告
According to the records I pulled,
这女人已经失踪5年多了
This woman has been missing for over five years.
灵书妙探
第一季第五集
她是个问题少女
She had a troubled childhood.
十几二十岁的时候吸毒
Drug problems in her teens and 20s.
我知道
I know.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
我看过案件档案  后来她戒掉了毒瘾
I read the case file. She kicked the habit.
认识塞缪尔·卡瓦诺后结婚
Met and married Samuel Kavanaugh.
她在餐厅工作  而他是银行经理
She worked in a restaurant. He managed a bank.
他们有两个孩子
They have two kids.
你什么时候看的档案
When did you read the case file?
你去厕所的时候
When you were in the little girls' room.
我只去了  大概一分钟
I was gone for, like, a minute.
一目十行
Speed-reader.
我在纽约公共图书馆待这么多年的
That's all I picked up from my years stranded
唯一收获
In the New York public library.
需要克利夫笔记  学习指南丛书吗
Would you like the cliffsnotes?
或者本案的卡塞尔笔记
Or in this case, the Castle notes?
卡塞尔  你怎么就敢肯定
Castle, how do you know
你没有忽略一些重点
You didn't miss something important?
比如梅勒妮失踪之后  她的丈夫等了一天
Like, after Melanie disappeared, her husband waited a day
-才打电话报警  -一天
- Before he called the cops. - A day?
这不合常理
That doesn't make any sense.
看到第三段你就明白了
Until you get to the third paragraph.
在梅勒妮结婚之前
Before Melanie was married,
她上演过一次真实版落跑新娘
She was what is now referred to as a "runaway bride."
据她丈夫说
According to her husband,
在他们的婚礼前
She ran away a whole two weeks
她曾经离家整整2周
Before their wedding day.
然后她回来了
Mm-hmm, and the she came back.
他们渡过了三年的幸福时光
Three years happily ever after,
她再一次失踪  不久又回来了
She disappears again and comes back.
反反复复  一共三次
Lather, rinse, repeat three times.
行踪飘忽不定  难以追查
No indication of where she went.
离家出走  她一定有原因
Well, she must've had a reason for running away.
不一定  我不是对她有偏见
Hmm. I'm not judging her.
有些人喜欢刺激  讨厌日复一日的生活
Some people love the institution, hate the day-to-day.
你是其中之一吗  卡塞尔
Are you one of those people, Castle?
我想  我只是还没遇到真命天女
I guess I just haven't met the right girl.
所以她的丈夫没有报警是因为
So that's why her husband didn't call the cops.
她曾经离家出走过
She'd done it before.
当时负责此案的警官也认为合情合理
Seemed reasonable to the detective at the time.
没有任何证据证明是谋杀
There's no evidence of foul play,
所以就这么结案了
So the detective just closed the case.
已经五年了
Five years,
难道她丈夫还认为她只是离家出走
And her husband thought she just ran away?
我想  该是时候告诉他
Guess it's time to tell him
他的落跑新娘终于回来了
His runaway bride finally came home.
是谁
Who is it?
纽约市警察局
New York city police department.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
我是贝克特探长  你是塞缪尔·卡瓦诺吗
Detective Beckett. Are you Samuel Kavanaugh?
谁
Who?
塞缪尔·卡瓦诺  记录显示他住在这儿
Samuel Kavanaugh. Our records indicate that he lives here.
不  你们一定是找错房间了
No, you must have the wrong apartment.
9-1-7
9-1-7?
是的  但我住在这
Yeah, but I live here,
而且我叫罗杰  不叫山姆
And my name is Roger. It's not Sam.
那你认识塞缪尔·卡瓦诺吗
Do you know any Samuel Kavanaugh?
不认识  怎么了
No. What's this about?
你在这住了多久了
How long have you lived here?
大概八个月
About eight months.
已经过去五年了  他可能已经搬走了
Well, it's been five years. He could've moved.
很抱歉打断你们
Well, yeah, I hate to break it to you,
如果你们是要找  之前住在这儿的人
But if you're looking for the guy who lived here before me,
他没搬走  他被谋杀了
He didn't move. He was murdered.
等等
Wait!
-贝克特  -什么事
- Hey, Beckett. - Yeah?
塞缪尔·卡瓦诺
Samuel Kavanaugh--
大约一年前  他在一间杂货店外中枪
Shot outside a grocery store about a year ago.
小口径枪支  胸部中了两枪
Small caliber, double tap to the chest.
钱包和贵重物品被抢走
Wallet and valuables missing.
可怜的倒霉蛋  老婆失踪了
Poor schlub's wife disappears
四年后  他又遇到劫案被杀
Four years later, he gets shot in a mugging.
是啊  有什么值得奇怪的
Yeah, what are the odds?
没有  除非这些之间是有关联的
No, unless they're connected.
什么  相隔四年的两起谋杀案
What, four years between the murders
一个被冻成冰棍  一个被枪杀
One's a popsicle, one just got popped.
这之间怎么可能有联系
How could they possibly be connected?
也许他们夫妇二人陷入了
Maybe he and his wife got into something
无法摆脱的麻烦
They couldn't get out of,
也许和她曾经吸毒有关
Maybe something to do with her drug habit.
你是说  某个瘾君子等了四年才杀了他
So some skell waits four years finished the job.
也许是丈夫终于发现了妻子的事
Maybe he finally figured out what happened to his wife
正准备去警局报案
And was about to go to the police with it.
我不相信
I don't believe it.
我写250页小说给你看  保证你相信
Give me 250 pages. I bet I could make you.
我们正在处理一桩谋杀案  卡塞尔
We're solving a murder, Castle,
不是在写书
Not writing a book.
就叫做  嗜血冰封
I would call it, "a chill runs through her veins."
我喜欢
Ooh, I like that.
成功  又来一本畅销书
"Bam," said the lady. Another best seller for me.
孩子们情况如何
What happened to the kids?
和梅勒妮的父母住在白平原
Living with Melanie's parents up in White Plains.
看来我要去白平原一趟了
Well, looks like I’m going to White Plains.
详查建筑工地
Canvass the construction site.
肯定有人看到过什么
Someone must've seen something.
是的  工头说
Yeah, the foreman said that, uh,
晚上总有流浪汉来找麻烦
They have a problem with the homeless at night,
所以我想晚点去那儿一趟
So I figured I’d go down there later,
看看能否在工地抓到他们
Try to catch 'em at the site.
流浪汉  白平原  流浪汉  白平原
Homeless, White Plains. Homeless, White Plains.
都有点诡异
They're both kinda creepy.
好吧
All right.
吓到你们了吗
Did I scare ya?
戴维逊先生
Mr. Davidson?
是的  女士  是我
Yes, ma'am. That's me.
能找个地方谈谈吗
Is there somewhere we could talk?
好的  我们进去谈
Yes. Why don't we go inside?
姑娘们  别到马路上玩
Girls, don't play in the street, okay?
好的  外公一会儿就出来
All right. Grandpa will be out in a minute.
我想我们早就知道
I- I think we've both known for a while now
梅勒妮不会回家来了
That Melanie was not going to come home.
你还记得
What do you remember
在她失踪的前几天发生过什么吗
About the days leading up to her disappearance?
我们几天前和她聊过
Well, uh, we talked to her a couple days before--
我是说  我太太跟她聊过
Uh, my wife did, I mean.
看起来一切正常
Everything seemed fine.
没有任何迹象显示她要离开吗
She didn't indicate in any way that she was leaving?
没有
No.
我们知道你女儿有些问题
We're aware your daughter had some issues.
那跟她的失踪没有关系
That had nothing to do with what happened here.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
你现在的语气就跟
You know, now you sound like
第一个处理这案子的警察一样
The cop who first had the case--
确信她出走了
Convinced she'd run away,
确信她还在吸毒
Convinced she was still on drugs.
可你不那么想
But you didn't think that.
梅勒妮
Melanie...
或许不是最好的母亲
Wasn't the greatest of moms...
但她爱她的孩子
But she loved her kids.
她永远也不会离开他们的
She would've never left them.
她的丈夫山姆怎么想
What about her husband Sam?
他也觉得是因为毒品
He thought it was drugs, too.
你们知道他等了一天
You know he waited over a day
才去报失踪的吗
Before he reported her missing?
她以前也出走过
She had run off before.
我不会否认这个
Look, I’m not gonna sit here and deny that,
但如果山姆觉得我女儿又吸毒了
But if Sam thought our daughter was in trouble,
为什么她失踪后他没有马上报警
Why didn't he report her missing right away?
为什么他没有寻求帮助
Why didn't he call for help?
就算她被抓起来了
Even if she'd gotten locked up,
也会比现在好
She'd have been better off than--
天哪  这有什么区别
Oh, what the hell's the difference? I mean,
该问这些问题的时间是五年前
The time to ask these questions was five years ago,
但处理这案子的警察
But the cop who was on the case
却什么都没有问
Then didn't want to ask them.
听起来他们对当初的调查
Sounds like they were pretty unhappy
很不满意
With the original investigation.
他们完全有理由不满
Yeah, well, they had every reason to be.
当初负责此案的警察
The guy whose case it was--
你认识吗
You know him?
不认识   斯隆警官比我早当警察很久
No. Detective Sloan was before my time.
他还在职吗
He still around?
如果在新泽西当警长也算的话
Well, if you count being a sheriff in Jersey,
那他还在职
Then yeah, he's still around.
梅勒妮·卡瓦诺
Melanie Kavanaugh.
这么多年后总算找到她了
So she was finally found after all these years, huh?
只找到了她的尸体
She wasn't found. Her body was.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear that.
从我接手那个案子
You know, from the moment I took that case,
我就觉得结果不会好
I figured it was gonna end bad.
她的父母告诉我们
Her parents led us to believe
你很肯定她是离家出走了
That you were pretty sure that she'd run off.
她死亡还是离家出走
Her being found dead and her running off
就她的历史来看并不矛盾
Are not exactly incompatible, not with her history.
她的父母还认为你的调查
Her parents also believe your investigation
从没偏离过她的历史
Never made it past her history.
我调查的是失踪  并不是谋杀
I was on a missing persons, not a murder.
你们有具尸体
You have a dead body.
我有的只是一个有吸毒史的女人
All I had was a- a woman with a drug habit
还有  失踪史
And a history of, uh, disappearing.
但是他的丈夫在她失踪一天后
And a husband who didn't report her missing
才报的警
For over a day.
别放马后炮了
Don't you dare play Monday morning quarterback with me.
亲爱的  他很合作
Look, sweetheart, he cooperated.
他主动让犯罪现场调查组进屋查看
He voluntarily allowed C.S.U. Into their apartment.
我所有的要求  他都照办了
Anything I asked, he did.
你知道他也被谋杀了吗
Did you know he was murdered, too?
在街上被枪杀的  一年多前
Gunned down on the street, over a year ago.
你们想从我这儿知道什么
Look, what do you want from me?
我们已经报告了她在费城
We had reports of her in Philly with
有个磕药的前男友的
A meth head ex-boyfriend.
那都是过去的事了
I mean, it was what it was.
但你从没去调查一下
But you didn't even go down to check it out.
不需要  已经报告了
Didn't need to. Had reports.
对  她丈夫最好的朋友查尔斯·怀勒说的
Right. From her husband's best friend Charles Wyler.
-所以呢  -所以他有可能会不客观
- So? - He's not exactly an impartial observer.
他有自己的生意  有家庭
The guy owned his own business. He had a family.
他还是个退伍老兵
He was a war vet.
没理由怀疑他的证词
I saw no reason to doubt his word.
而且  费城很远
Plus, Philly's a pretty long drive.
她只是失踪了
She was only missing back then.
不  警长  她当时已经死了
No, sheriff, she was already dead.
你只是不知道而已
You just didn't know it yet.
如果哪天我失踪了
I ever disappear,
你别让这家伙调查我的案子
Make sure this guy's not on my case.
我讨厌他那样的警察
I hate cops like him.
像他那样的人  思想僵化
Guys like him-- things only make sense if they fit in a box.
他们固执己见  让凶手跑了
So they make 'em fit, and murderer go free.
你父亲也有这样的遭遇吗
Is that what happened to your dad?
我父亲
My dad?
我注意到你的手表
I noticed your watch.
是你父亲的  是吗
It's your dad's, right?
所以你戴着它
That's why you wear it?
你找到目击者了
You find a witness?
对  一个流浪汉
Yeah, homeless guy.
给他点钱他就说了
A couple of bucks jogged his memory.
他说看到一辆有凹痕的黄色卡车
Said he saw a dented yellowtruck
开到了这个位置
Pull up to the site.
一个强壮的家伙从后面拉出个大包
Heavyset guy pulls a large bag out of the back,
而他再出来的时候
And when he comes out,
包不见了
He doesn't have the bag anymore.
你怎么找到这里的
How'd you find this place?
他还记得卡车的
Guy also remembered the word "storage"
一边写着  仓库
Written on the side of the truck.
我们找了全部仓库
We searched all the storage
发现这里用黄色卡车
And found that this one uses yellow trucks.
这卡车是谁的
So who owns the trucks?
根据车管部的资料  是阿尔伯特·波朗德
According to the D.M.V., Albert Bolland.
什么尸体
What body?
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
目击者说看到有人开着你的黄色卡车
A witness saw someone driving one of your yellow trucks
去弃尸
And dumping the body.
你说谎  没人看到
You're lying. No one saw.
也许你该先否认去过那里吧
Ouch. Wow. Maybe you should've tried denying it first?
我来帮帮你
Let me help you.
梅勒妮·卡瓦诺  两个孩子的母亲
Melanie Kavanaugh, mother of two.
山姆·卡瓦诺的妻子
Wife of Sam Kavanaugh.
好吧  我承认弃尸
Okay, look, I dumped her,
-但我发誓我没有  -你没有杀她  对吗
- But I swear I didn't-- - You didn't kill her, right?
对
That's right.
我发现了她
I found her.
我不知道她在那儿
I never even knew she was here.
哪儿
What do you mean "here"?
在六楼
Sixth floor.
如果房客欠租金的话
Renters were in arrears.
我们通常给他们三个月期限
We usually give 'em three months,
然后撬锁卖货来抵欠款
And then we cut the locks and we sell their belongings.
但这次  我只发现了个冷藏柜
Only this time, all I find is a freezer
插在照明电源上
Plugged into a light outlet,
顺便说一下  这种行为完全不合法
Which, by the way, is totally illegal.
你不觉得
You didn't think
把尸体塞在冷藏柜里是违法的吗
It was illegal to store a dead body in a freezer?
你以为我知道吗
You think I knew?
我打开冰箱的时候  差点犯心脏病了
When I opened it up, I nearly had a heart attack.
你可以叫警察的
You could call the cops
然后上账簿网((纽约时报旗下报纸)头版
So I could make the front page of "the ledger"?
这对我的生意太好了
Yeah, that's good for business.
如果是黑帮作案怎么办
What if it's a mob hit?
我也有家庭
I mean, I got a family.
她也有家庭
So did she.
所以是你找到的她
So you find her.
经过理性思考
Next logical step--
把她扔到了建筑工地
Dump her at a construction site?
我认识个人在那儿工作
I know a guy who works over there.
所以当我发现尸体时
So when I find the body, I figure,
我就想到了那个地方
That's the place, right?
带我们去你找到她的地方
Show us where you found her.
在这里五年了
Five years in there.
没有人应该被这么对待
Nobody deserves that.
他们通过什么方式为这个仓库付款
How'd they make payments for the unit?
支票还是信用卡
Check? Credit card?
现金  每六个月付一次
Cash. Every six months.
但他们有三个多月没付了
But like I said, they were three months overdue.
最后一次付款
Puts the last payment
是在她丈夫被杀两个月后
At two months after her husband was killed.
死人是不会付款的
How to make payments when he was dead ?
你办公室的摄像头
That camera in your office--
有没有拍下付款的人
You got footage of the guy who made payments?
已经是九个月以前的事了
That was nine months ago.
我们一次只保存近两周的录像
We keep maybe two weeks at a time.
看起来斯隆是对的
Looks like Sloan was right.
山姆·卡瓦诺跟此案无关
Sam Kavanaugh didn't have anything to do with it.
如果不是山姆  那又是谁呢
Well, if not Sam, then who?
我们有空调的
You know, we have air-conditioning.
我只是想搞清楚
I'm just trying to figure out
为什么有人会把尸体放到冷藏柜里
Why someone would put a dead body in a freezer.
是妮奇·希特  还是贝克特探长遇到的难题
Is this a Nikki Heat or detective Beckett question?
-贝克特  -这就对了
- Beckett.  - Oh, that's right.
妮奇·希特的问题
The Nikki Heat thing was about
是关于在自洁式烤箱里焚尸
Incinerating a body in a self-cleaning oven.
你把东西放到冰箱里是为了以后用
I mean, you put things in a freezer to keep 'em for later,
但一旦把它们放进来
But once they're there,
你就很少再会拿出来用了
You rarely ever go back.
如果我把一具尸体放进冰箱
If I was putting a body in a freezer,
肯定是因为我想藏尸
It'd be because I was trying to hide it.
直到不再为仓库付款
Until you stopped paying for the storage space.
是我不付款  还是我不能付款
Did I stop, or did something stop me?
像这样的家庭时光  我永远也忘不了
It's family moments like these I will never forget.
要是和一个很好的心理学家
With a good therapist,
或许我会的
Hopefully I will.
怀勒先生
Mr. Wyler,
当初调查梅勒妮失踪案的警察
The detective investigating Melanie's disappearance
说你告诉他
Said that you told him that
梅勒妮去费城看前男友了 是吗
She went to an ex-boyfriend in Philadelphia?
没有  我只告诉了他山姆对我说的事情
No, I only told him what Sam told me.
山姆告诉你的
Sam told you?
她在婚礼前去过那里
It's where she went before the wedding
结婚后又去了几次
And a few times after.
但你不确定这次她去了哪里
But you're not sure that's where she went.
只有这样才说得通
It's the only thing that made sense.
梅勒妮是个好人
Melanie was a good person,
但她很麻烦
But Melanie was... Troubled.
有时候心情不好
Sometimes when things got hard,
她就出去疯去了
She'd go out and score, you know?
醉醺醺地回家  骂山姆毁了她的生活
Come home high, accuse Sam of ruining her life.
他已经给了她一切
He'd given her everything.
你还记得她前男友的名字吗
Do you remember the name of the boyfriend?
凯文·亨森
Kevin Henson
如果梅勒妮出了什么事
If something happened to Melanie,
他就是那个唯一知情的人
He's the one who would know what.
凯文·亨森  梅勒妮的前男友
Kevin Henson-- Melanie's ex-boyfriend.
他在新泽西南部戒了一年毒
He's serving a year for meth in south Jersey.
他刚好在是在仓库
He went in just after the last payment
收到最后一次付款后进去的
Was made on the storage unit.
他没法儿付款  仓库的人就发现了尸体
He stops payment, the storage guy finds her body.
太巧合了
Quite a coincidence.
而且当她丈夫被杀的时候
And he was also on the outside
他正好离开了戒毒所
When her husband was whacked.
听起来我们有必要去趟南新泽西
Sounds like he's worth a trip to south Jersey.
你曾经爱过吗  探长
You ever been in love, detective?
它让你疯狂
It makes you do crazy things.
比如说杀人
Like kill someone?
梅勒妮和我  我们在一起的时候
Mel and I, when we were together,
时间就像静止了
Time just stopped.
但在我们相爱的第一天  她和我
But even the first day, her and me--
我们就知道  我们不合适
We both knew it was never gonna work.
她的父母永远也不会
God knows her folks were never gonna
让宝贝女儿跟这样的人在一起
Let their little girl end up with some...
一个满身纹身的瘾君子
Tatted-up addict.
但有时候
But sometimes, see,
有时候我们单独在一起
Sometimes when we were alone together...
有时候我们几乎相信  我们会在一起
Sometimes we almost believed.
她想要离开山姆
She was gonna leave Sam.
所以她来找你
That's why she came to see you.
她发现她丈夫有了外遇
She found out he was having an affair.
他想要离开她  拿走孩子的监护权
He was gonna leave her and get custody of the kids,
你知道  因为她吸毒
You know, because of the drugs.
她想要我和她一起走  带着孩子就此消失
She wanted me to go with her, take the kids, just disappear.
所以你做了什么
So what'd you do?
只是送她上了公共汽车
Put her on a bus.
你送她离开了
You sent her away?
她想要的  我给不了她
What she wanted, I couldn't give her.
第二天  我就去了戒毒所
Checked into rehab the next day.
我想如果我可以戒掉毒瘾
I thought if I could get clean...
所以她失踪的时候  我正在戒毒所里
That's where I was when she disappeared.
而我出来的时候  她死了
By the time I got out, she was dead.
你怎么肯定她死了呢
How could you be sure she was dead.
她没再打过电话
She stopped calling.
如果她还活着  她会给我打电话的
If she was alive, she would've called.
外遇可以解释很多问题
Well, an affair certainly explains a lot.
山姆杀了梅勒妮
Sam kills Melanie,
或是他和他的情人一起杀了梅勒妮
Or he and his lover kill Melanie together.
那又是谁杀了山姆
Well, then who kills Sam?
他的情人
The lover,
她为他做了这么多  他却想退出
When Sam backs out after all she's done for him.
如果他背信弃义
It's not like she could go to the police
她可不会去警察局
If he broke his promise.
你怎么会想出这些事情的  卡塞尔
How do you come up with these things, Castle?
不是我想出  是它们自己冒出来的
I did not come up with this one. They did.
好吧  从你们男人的角度看
Okay, you speak "guy."
如果山姆有情人  他最好的朋友会知道吗
If Sam had a lover, would his best friend know about it?
当然
Yes.
探长
Detective.
你对我们撒谎了  怀勒先生
You lied to us, Mr. Wyler.
什么
Excuse me?
你认为梅勒妮的失踪
You don't think maybe it's relevant your buddy Sam
和山姆当时的外遇无关吗
Had an affair right about the time Melanie disappeared?
这是很久以前的事了
That was a long time ago.
把所有人拖下水有意义吗
The point of dragging everybody through the mud?
他们的孩子还没受够吗
Haven't their kids been through enough?
他们就不能得到点安宁吗
Don't they deserve some peace?
他们应该得到的
What they deserve is to know
是他们母亲被害的真相
What happened to their mother.
伊丽莎白·芙缇
Elizabeth Forte.
她叫伊丽莎白·芙缇
Elizabeth Forte is her name.
她在山姆的银行里工作
She worked with Sam at his bank.
芙缇太太  我是贝克特探长
Mrs. Forte, I'm Detective Beckett.
这是里克·卡塞尔
This is Rick Castle.
为什么带我来这儿
Why am I here?
塞缪尔·卡瓦诺  这个名字耳熟吗
Does the name Samuel Kavanaugh ring a bell?
他怎么了
What about him?
我们发现了他妻子梅勒妮的尸体
We found the body of his wife Melanie.
根据尸体情况判断
From the looks of it,
她的死亡时间
She was killed somewhere around the time
就在你俩有风流韵事的时候
The two of you were having an affair.
我不明白你是什么意思
I'm afraid I don't know what you mean.
想让我把那些事儿
Do you really want me to
都挖出来吗  芙缇太太
Start digging around in your life, Mrs. Forte.
因为那正是我将会做的
Because that's exactly what I will do.
我会检查你以前的通话记录
I'll go through your old phone records,
你的信用卡帐单
Your credit card statements.
如果还不行  我还会找你丈夫谈谈
I'll even talk to your husband if I have to.
别  求你别这样做
Please. Please don't do that.
加里对此一无所知
Gary doesn't know anything about it.
那就把你知道的告诉我们
Just walk us through what you know.
我调往市区分行时认识了山姆
I met Sam when I got transferred to the downtown branch.
那时他负责新开户
He was in new accounts.
当时我们都不快乐
We were both pretty unhappy at the time.
-你们在一起多久  -不太久  半年
- How long was the affair?  - Not long. Six months.
-为什么分手  -我意识到我是爱我丈夫的
- Why did it end?  - I realized I loved my husband.
拜托  没人会因为
Please. No one ends an affair
还爱着另一半而结束外遇的
Because they realize they're still loving.
他们结束一切是因为害怕
They end an affair because they're scared.
害怕事件升级
Scared of taking it to the next level.
害怕被抓奸在床
Scared of being found out.
害怕他们的人生被毁
Scared of ruining their life.
那么
So
说说  伊丽莎白  你害怕什么呢
Tell us, Elizabeth, what were you scared of?
他
Him.
我害怕山姆
I was scared of Sam.
-为什么  -他开始问我  如果他妻子不在
- Why?  - He started to ask me what I would do
我会怎么做
If he wasn't with his wife.
如果她消失不见
If she wasn't in the picture anymore.
那是什么时候的事
And when was that?
她失踪的前几个星期
A few weeks before she disappeared.
当我发现她失踪时
When I found out she was missing,
我与他断绝了关系  他非常生气
I broke things off. He became angry.
事情变得很糟糕
It got so bad that
我不得不调往另一家分行
I had to transfer to another branch.
你  抱歉  你不得不
You... I'm sorry. You had to, uh...
五年了  芙缇太太
Five years, Mrs. Forte.
整整五年  你居然从没站出来揭发
Five whole years, and you never came forward?
就算山姆杀了梅勒妮又怎么样
What's it matter if Sam killed Melanie?
他死了  他们俩都死了
He's dead. They're both dead.
有什么关系呢
What's the matter anymore?
你是怎么做到的  山姆
How'd you do it, Sam?
哪里跑  叛徒
Run, rebel.
你永远无法打败沃尔塔(模玩人物)的军队
But you'll never defeat the forces of Voltar.
去死吧  沃尔塔  沃尔塔的手下
Death to Voltar! Death to the Voltarians!
我感觉到你内心的恐惧
I sense fear in you.
你感觉错了吧
You sense nothing!
有人看到我的钱包了吗
Has anyone seen my purse?
妈妈  我们完全投入在战斗中
Mom, we are totally doing battle on the field of honor.
你多大了
How old are you?
正好买得起最高级的激光枪
Old enough to afford top-of-the-line laser tag.
我死了  妈妈
I'm dead! Mom!
现在伏尔泰永远无法统治全宇宙了
Now Voltar will never rule the Omniverse.
有人叫了吃的吗
Someone order food?
-没有  -没有
- No.  - No.
我还是去看下
I'd better check this out.
是谁啊
Who is it?
贝克特警官
Detective Beckett.
亲爱的  有客人来啦
Darling, are we entertaining?
爸爸
Dad.
注意礼貌
Manners.
对
Right.
请进  请进  欢迎
Come on in, please, why don't you? Welcome...
-谢谢  -欢迎来我们家
- Thank you.  - To our house.
当然
You bet.
还记得我母亲玛莎吧
You, um, you remember my mother Martha.
当然还有阿丽克西斯
And Alexis. Of course.
记得 你们好
Yes. Hello.
要不要喝点什么
Can I... Make you a drink?
我觉得像
I feel like...
阿尔弗雷德(《蝙蝠侠》的老管家)
Alfred in the batcave
第一次进蝙蝠洞
For the first time.
蝙蝠侠的粉丝  我猜
Batman fan. Figures.
什么
Why?
类似的起源故事吗
Similar origin stories?
失去所爱  激发人一生与犯罪作斗争
Loss of a loved one leads to a life of fighting crime.
你就是那个与罪恶富豪做斗争的人
Yes, well, you are the multimillionaire crime fighter.
在那儿  我给书列提纲
That's, uh, where I outline my books.
真有趣
That's funny.
很像我们的
Looks a lot like our...
破案的分析图
Murder board.
只是我的是假的
Yeah, except mine's fake.
出什么事儿了
Something wrong?
我找不出来
I can't find it.
找不出来什么
Find what?
答案
The answer.
是山姆杀的
It was Sam.
一切合理  结局圆满
Everything fits. It's a good ending.
但没有证据  只是推测
Yeah, but without proof, it's just a theory.
那个家庭  那两个孩子
And that family...those kids...
他们需要的不只是推测
They need more than just a theory.
他们得知道一切  我也是
They need to know. I need to know.
那么  你觉得该有个结局
Well, you have an ending.
如果想彻底弄清  你得往回调查
You want the rest, you need to work backwards.
这样事情才有个了断
You need to finish the story.
你知道结局  你知道谁是凶手
You have an ending. You have your killer.
你只需要把手里的事实整合在一起
You just have to put it all together with the facts at hand.
什么事实
The facts?
事实是  他们有两个小孩
Fact...They had two small children.
-那所以呢  -根据警方的供述
- So?  - Based on police statements.
丈夫上班的时候
They didn't have baby sitter.
他们并没有请保姆
With him at work.
妻子失踪时
She would've had to have been
应该是和孩子们在一起
With the kids she disappeared.
但山姆说当晚  后来她出去了
But Sam said that she left later that night.
不过门卫也没证实这一点
Which the doorman was never able to corroborate.
如果她一直都在家  那么
So if she was there and she never left, then...
那她就是在家里被杀的
Then she was murdered in the apartment.
还有一点  他住在曼哈顿
Another fact he lived in Manhattan.
和市里的多数人一样  他没有车
And like most people in the city, he didn't own a car.
那么住在曼哈顿的模范丈夫
So what is a good husband...
会怎么处理他妻子的尸体呢
...to do living in Manhattan with his wife's body?
他不能把尸体留在家里
He can't leave it in the apartment.
他也不能带着尸体穿过大厅
He can't walk out the lobby with it.
那么  唯一的问题是
So the only question is...
他是怎样把尸体运到仓库的
How did he get the body to the storage unit?
他
He...
可以  不行
Hey, could...No.
-知道什么有用吗  -什么
- You know what helps?  - Yeah?
有时当我试着弄明白
Sometimes when I'm trying to figure out...
小说里的角色会怎么做
... How a character of man does something.
我会去犯罪现场走走
I will walk the crime scene.
有一次  我试想
This one time, I was trying to figure out...
怎样把人从帝国大厦里扔出去
How to throw someone off the Empire State Building.
当时《西雅图不眠夜》刚上映
And that movie "Sleepless in Seattle" had just come out.
好多寂寞的女人靠近我
Oh, so many lonely women approached me.
想着我是她们的汤姆·汉克斯  我就
Thinking I was their Tom Hanks. I got...
卡塞尔
Castle.
关键是  你应该了解凶手的想法
The point is, you want to get into a killer's head.
去凶手去过的地方
Go to where the killer was ...
看有什么需要解决的问题
... And see what problems here to face.
实地考察
Field trip?
他们告诉我  他是被劫杀
They told me he was shot in a mugging.
现在你们告诉我
And now you're telling me
他是在这屋子被杀的
He was killed here in my appartment.
不是他  是他妻子
Not him,  his wife.
她妻子  这是个什么样的家庭呀
His wife? What kind of family was this?
行了  这样  我和你结婚了
All right. So you and I are married.
我们没有结婚
We are not married.
放松  只是假装
Relax. It's just pretend.
-不想假装  -怕自己喜欢这感觉
- I don't want to pretend.  - Scared you'll like it?
好  如果我们结婚了  现在我就想离
Okay, if we're married, I want a divorce.
你们俩一直像这样吗
Are you two like this all the time?
-对  -对
- Yes.  - Yes.
好了  我们没有结婚  但是他们结了
All right, we're not married, but they were.
我们就当门卫说的是对的
Let's see the doorman's right.
梅勒妮大概4点钟回家
Now Melanie gets home about 4 o'clock.
她就得给孩子们做晚饭
She'd have to make dinner for the kids.
然后山姆回家了
Then Sam comes home.
银行下班是6点左右
Bank hours, around 6 o'clock.
孩子们已经吃完了
Figure the kids have already eaten.
那么他们在干什么
So they're, what...
在卧室看电视
...Um... Watching TV in the bedroom.
在我的卧室吗
In my bedroom?
别打岔  讨论得激烈呢
We're on a roll.
-他们吵起来  -关于出轨的事儿
- They have a fight.  - About the affair.
-还有费城的事儿  -吵得越来越凶
- About Philadelphia.  - Things get heated.
然后她转过头去
And she turns her head...
他砸向她
He whacks her with something.
用锅  或是平底锅
A pot. Or a pan.
砰  打破了她的头  玩完了
Bam. Fractures her skull. It's over.
只是孩子们还在卧室里
Except the kids are still in the bedroom.
他得想个办法
He's got to figure out a way of
不能让孩子们看见他移尸
Getting her out of the apartment without them see it.
门厅一旁的厕所
Hallway bathroom.
他需要拖延时间
He needed to buy time.
对  所以他
Okay, so he, um...
把尸体放进了浴缸
...He puts the body in the tub.
-关上门  -等一下
- Closes the door...  - Wait!
然后告诉孩子们  妈妈去商店了
And tells the kids that mom went to the store.
根据案件档案
Which, according to the case file.
门卫一直都没证实这点
The doorman was never able to substantiate.
好  那么没有车
Okay, so no car.
他是怎么把尸体移出公寓呢
How does he get the body out of the apartment?
也许他叫了辆出租车
Maybe he hailed a cab.
也许出租车司机和门卫还
Yeah, maybe the cabbie and the doorman...
帮他把尸体塞进后备箱呢
... Helped him stuff the body in the trunk.
-现在这活儿小费多少啊  -那个门卫
- How much do you tip for that these days?  - The doorman.
卡塞尔  我在开玩笑呢
Castle, I'm joking.
要是尸体在带出公寓时
What if the body was already in the freezer...
就已经放在冷藏柜里了呢
... When he took it out of the apartment.
冷藏柜  那他得要一辆卡车
Freezer? He'd have needed a truck.
在我住的大楼里  如果你
In my building, if you have...
有什么东西要接受或递送
Something picked or deliver.
-得签字  -对  这里也是啊
- You have to sign for it.  - Yeah, here, too.
递送那么大个东西
A delivery that big.
你就得在登记册上登记
You have to sign the ledger.
登记册
The ledger?
登记册就在楼下门卫那里
The doorman's ledger downstairs.
对  那是我的名字
Yeah, that's my name.
我知道那是五年前的事儿了  马什太太
I know it was five years ago, Mrs. Marsh.
但那天唯一的递送  就是送到你家
But the only delivery that day was to your apartment.
如果你还记得任何
If you remember anything at all...
有关那次递送的事儿
... About the delivery...
我记得我得下楼
I... I remember I had to go downstairs
澄清那事儿
And sort everything out.
澄清那事儿  是什么意思
What do you mean "sort everything out"?
我告诉门卫我从没定过冷藏柜
I told the doorman I never ordered a freezer.
但那家伙还是把它送了上来
But the guy brought it on up.
当我和门卫还在讲话时
He loaded it on the freight elevator.
他就把它装进货运电梯里
While I was talking to the doorman.
那您下去时发生了什么
So what happened when you were downstairs?
我告诉门卫  他们又把地址搞错了
I told the doorman they got the wrong apartment again.
但当我回到楼上时  那家伙已经走了
And then by the time I got back upstairs, the guy was gone.
这和那个失踪的女人有关系吗
Does this have anything to do with that missing woman?
对  有关系
Yeah, it does.
因为已经给另外一个警察讲了
Yeah, 'cause I already told the other cop.
斯隆警官吗
Detective Sloan?
我不知道他叫什么
I don't know his name.
但我把所有事儿都告诉他了
But I told him everything.
和对你们说的一样
Same as you.
我不明白了
I don't get it.
如果斯隆有这位老太太的记录
If Sloan had that woman's report.
他为什么没追查呢
Why didn't he just follow up?
他用不着这样
He wasn't looking for this story.
他已经把它记录下来了
He'd already written it.
那跟我们在查尔斯·怀勒的店外
That's the same kind of truck...
看到的的卡车是一样的
...We saw outside Charles Wyler's store.
他肯定和他们签订了合同的
He must have a contract with them.
如果你想请人帮忙搬重物
If you wanted some help with some heavy lifting.
你会打电话给谁呢
Who would you call?
你最好的朋友
Your best friend.
我们通过送货车租用信息
We can trace the rental of the delivery truck
找到了你  怀勒先生
To you, Mr. Wyler
如果你想的话  我可以找那位
If you want,  I can bring the lady you
你送冷藏柜的太太来认人
Delivered the freezer to  in to identify you.
我和梅勒妮的事没有任何关系
Look, I had nothing to do with what happened to Melanie.
别的你都说谎了  现在也一样吧
You lied about everything else. Why not about this?
我根本没理由伤害她
I never had any reason to hurt her.
但是山姆有  对吧
But Sam did, right?
她一直跑回前男友身边
I mean, she kept going back to her ex-boyfriend.
作为一个男人能忍多久呢
How much can a guy take?
他那天晚上给我打了电话
He called me that night.
他说
He said...
他需要我马上去一趟
He needed me to come over right away.
我到的时候孩子们都睡了
When I got there, the kids were asleep,
梅勒妮在浴缸里
And Melanie was in the tub...
装在西装袋里
In a garment bag.
他说她扑向他  他失控了
He said she came at him, and he just snapped.
我想说
Here's an idea
与其杀了她  为什么不离婚呢
Instead of killing her, why not just get a divorce?
你觉得我不知道这是犯法的吗
You don't think I know how wrong this was?
那为什么要冒险  去搬尸体
Why did you take the risk? Why did you move that body?
因为这个错他承受不起
Because he made a very bad mistake.
孩子怎么办
And what about the kids?
他们的妈妈已经死了
Their mom is dead.
如果他去坐牢的话
If he goes to prison...
所以你安排了卡车
So you arranged for the truck.
他说绝不可能找到他身上的
He said it could never be traced back to him.
所以我们送冷藏柜给那个老太太
That's why we sent the freezer to the old lady,
所以我租了仓库
That's why I rented out the storage space,
因为我们知道警察会盯上山姆
Because we knew the cops would look at Sam.
是你付租金的吗
You made the payments?
因为山姆不能冒任何险
Sam couldn't take any chances.
他给我现金  我就
He'd give me the cash, and I’d...
一年去两次
Stop by twice a year.
一共五年了
For five years.
貌似比搬走她容易的多
It seemed a lot easier than moving her.
那为什么没继续付租金了
Why did you stop paying?
对梅勒妮的死  我很抱歉
Look, I'm truly sorry about what happened to Melanie.
但我应该怎么做
But what was I supposed to do,
一直付一辈子租金吗
Keep paying for the rest of my life?
检察官会保证这一点的  怀勒先生
The D.A. will make sure of that, Mr. Wyler.
她的尸体被扔掉是因为
Her body gets dumped because
那个叫怀勒的家伙没付租金
This guy Wyler didn't pay a bill?
-这简直  -可以这么说  很冷酷
- That's... - You can say it. Pretty cold.
讽刺的是  自私的行为最终使真相大白
Ironic that such a selfish act ultimately revealed the truth.
有人一直知道真相
There were people who knew the truth all along.
但他们选择沉默
They just chose not to come forward.
但报应回来
Still, karma comes back and
收拾了他老公
Puts a cap in her husband's ass.
所以世界是公平的
So all is right with the world.
我要去和梅勒妮的父母谈谈
I'm gonna go talk to Melanie's parents,
告诉他们都是怎么回事
Let 'em know how this all shook out.
你要来吗
You wanna come?
那个收到冷藏柜的老太太
The woman with the freezer delivery
说她和一个警察谈过
Told us she talked to a cop.
对  斯隆
Yeah. Sloan.
但他的报告里没写她的名字
Only he didn't list her name in his report.
他觉得不重要吧
He didn't feel that it was important.
毕竟他不信那是一起谋杀案
After all, he didn't believe he was looking at a murder.
那如果  你不是在调查谋杀案
Right, so if you're not investigating a murder,
为什么会询问邻居
Why would you talk to the neighbor
送冷藏柜的事情
About a freezer delivery?
肯定是冷藏柜的事
This must be some freezer.
马什太太您提起过一个警察
You mentioned a police officer, Mrs. Marsh.
我知道已经五年了  但您
I know it's been five years, but do you
我可没说过是五年前
I never said five years ago.
-他什么时候找的您  -去年
- When did he come see you? - Last year sometime.
我记得想过  为什么警察问我这些
I remember thinking, why is this cop asking me questions
只是关于我从没订过的冷藏柜
About a freezer I never ordered?
您还记得来找您的
Do you remember anything about
那个人的情况吗
The man who came to see you?
他年纪也大了
Uh, he was older.
穿制服吗
Uniform?
不  和你们一样是便服
No. Plain clothes like you.
灰白发  走路有点跛
He had gray hair, and he walked with a limp.
-本·戴维逊  -梅勒妮的父亲
- Ben Davidson. - Melanie's dad.
你可以什么也不做
You could just leave it like this.
山姆死了
Sam's dead.
老大很高兴
The captain's happy.
孩子们看起来也很快乐
Those kids look pretty happy.
这就是小说
That's the difference between a novel
和现实的不同  卡塞尔
And the real world, Castle.
警察不能决定故事怎样结束
A cop doesn't get to decide how the story ends.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
先生  您得和我
Sir, I'm gonna have to take you
去警局一趟
With me down to the station.
亲爱的  是谁
Who is it, honey?
本  怎么了
What is it, Ben?
我来这儿就是因为
So I'm here because
我问别人  有关冷藏柜的问题
I questioned a woman about a freezer?
可不是一般的冷藏柜  戴维逊先生
Not any freezer, Mr. Davidson.
是藏匿您女儿尸体的冷藏柜
The freezer that your daughter's body was stored in.
暂且  我们
For the moment, let's--
我们假设你说的是真的
Let's assume what you say is true.
会以什么罪起诉
What's the charge?
如果马什太太的回答造成山姆的死
If Mrs. Marsh's answer led to Sam's death,
会以谋杀起诉
Then the charge would be murder.
我一直在想山姆说的每件事
I kept going over everything Sam said,
他说的  那晚的一切
Everything he claimed happened that night,
直到得出一个结论
Until I came to the same conclusion
显然和你们的结论一样
That you both apparently did
梅勒妮根本没有活着离开过家
That Melanie never left her apartment alive.
马什太太的回答只确认了
Mrs. Marsh's answers merely confirmed
我已经知道的东西
What I already knew.
你的女婿就是凶手
That your son-in-law was a killer.
如果已经猜出山姆做了什么
If you had figured out what Sam had done,
你为什么不报警
Why not just go to the police?
他会在监狱度过余生
He would've gone to prison for the rest of his life.
是假如他被判有罪的话
If he'd been convicted.
但他们那时候没有尸体  记得吗
They didn't have a-a body at the time, remember?
他的律师会摆让梅勒妮受审  不是他
His lawyers would've put Melanie on trial, not him.
所以你就自己动手了
So you took matters into your own hands.
你确实理解了
Well, you can certainly understand
一个父亲的想法
How a father might want to,
他可能跟踪杀害他女儿的凶手
How he might follow his daughter's murderer
趁着漆黑的夜晚
One dark night when he was sure
他确信周围没人的时候
No other people would be around,
他可能是用从战争时期
How he might confront him with a gun
带回的枪指着他
He'd brought back from the war,
甚至同意用宽恕换取真相
Might even promise forgiveness in exchange for the truth.
听他承认罪行
And hearing his admission...
却又被愤怒压倒
Be overcome with rage.
每一次  他带孩子们来看我们
Every time he brought the girls to see us,
我都看到  我妻子的心又死去了一些
I watched a little piece of my wife die.
孙辈们的看望  应该使人感到生命可贵
A visit from your grandkids should be life-affirming,
不是提醒你  唯一的女儿是怎样被杀害的
Not a reminder of how your only child was murdered.
杀了他并不是解决办法
Killing him wasn't the answer.
我从来没说我杀了他
I never said I killed him.
我说的是  一个父亲可能有正当理由的
I said a father might be justified.
警察告诉我山姆是被劫杀的
The police told me Sam was shot in a robbery,
没有证据的话
And without evidence, there'd be little chance
几乎不可能抓到凶手
That his killer would ever be brought to justice.
所以我想  以后会知道是否如他所言
So I guess we'll find out if that's really true.
如果可以的话  我想要见律师
And I'd like to see a-a lawyer if I could.
不  甜心
No, sweetie,
我只是想和你说晚安
I just wanted to make sure I said good night.
好  我请吃草莓笑脸煎饼
You got it. Strawberry happy face pancakes on me.
再见
Later.
阿丽克西斯想我了
Alexis missed me.
你怎么知道
How did you know?
蜘蛛人的第六感
Spidey sense.
顺便说下  是我母亲
By the way, it was my mother,
不是父亲
Not my father.
我们本应一起去吃晚餐
We were supposed to go to dinner together--
我妈妈  爸爸和我
My mom, my dad and I
她该在餐馆和我们碰头
And she was gonna meet us at the restaurant,
但她没来
But she never showed.
两个小时后  我们回了家
Two hours later, we went home.
有个警官在等我们
And there was a detective waiting for us.
拉格林警官
Detective Raglin.
他们发现了她的尸体
They found her body.
她被人捅了
She had been stabbed.
抢劫吗
A robbery?
不
No.
她的钱  包和首饰都还在
She still had her money and purse and jewelry.
也没有性侵犯
And it wasn't a sexual assault, either.
他们归因于帮派暴力
They attributed it to gang violence.
随机事件
Random wayward event.
所以正像梅勒妮的案件
So just like in Melanie's case,
他们不能换个角度考虑
They couldn't think outside the box.
所以他们只是编了个不错的故事
So they just tried to package it up nicely,
根本没抓到凶手
And the killer was never caught.
你为什么戴那个表
Why do you wear the watch?
她的离开对我爸爸的打击非常大
My dad took her death hard.
他现在清醒了
He's sober now.
五年了
Five years.
所以
So...
这是为我挽救了的生命
This is for the life that I saved,
以及
And...
这是为我失去了的生命
This is for the life that I lost.
所以
So...
我猜你的妮奇·希特现在
I guess your Nikki Heat has
有背景故事了  卡塞尔
A backstory now, Castle.
我不知道
I don't know.
我确实喜欢白天妓女  晚上警察这点
I did kinda like the hooker-by-day, cop-by-night thing.
但是
But, uh...
我猜深情这个角度也行
I guess a heavy emotional angle could work, too.
别说是为了我
Don't bewilder your audiences
把你的读者弄糊涂了  卡塞尔
With substance on my account, Castle.
明天见  警官
Until tomorrow, detective.
你就不能说晚安吗
You can't just say "night"?
我是个作家  晚安这个词太无聊
I'm a writer. "night" is boring.
明天见  更充满希望
" Until tomorrow" is more... Hopeful.
我是个警察
I'm a cop.
晚安
Night.
爸爸
Hi, dad.
记住  这从来没发生过
Remember, this never happened.
我从来没来过这儿
I was never here.
我保证
You have my word.
谢谢
Thanks.
如果你告诉她是我干的
If you tell her I did this,
我会让你血溅当场
I will make you bleed.
我懂
Understood.
祝你好运
Good luck.